I say, Professor Fan.
Why are you always distancing yourself from the masses?
You're labeling me right from the start.
How am I distancing myself from the masses?
Look, let me count the ways for you.
You don't join the choir.
You don't sign up for the sports meet.
You don't learn ballroom dancing.
You don't attend the art class.
Anything related to group activities,
you don't participate in.
Last time everyone at Evergreen Residence caught a cold,
and you were the only one who didn't.
Tell me, aren't you out of touch with the masses?
So catching a cold
counts as a group activity to you?
Alright.
Stop reading.
All you do is read books all day long.
As if you're so learned.
What do you mean "as if"?
I am learned.
Learned, huh?
Then let me ask you a question.
Do you dare to answer?
I wouldn't dare.
Yeah, right.
With those little questions of yours.
Bring it on.
Good.
I'm asking then.
Go ahead.
There are two children.
They go to the same school.
They live in the same alley.
When the two children go to school,
one goes left out the door,
and one goes right out the door.
What's going on here?
That's too simple.
These two students,
their homes,
one lives to the left of the school,
and one lives to the right of the school.
Wrong.
The two children are neighbors.
They're no more than two meters apart.
How is that possible?
You don't know, do you?
The two kids live across from each other.
Such a simple little question,
and you can't even answer it.
And you call yourself learned.
That doesn't count.
That's too misleading.
Ask another one if you've got the guts.
Fine.
Then I'll ask another one.
Old Zhang is reading in his room.
Suddenly, the power goes out.
Why can Old Zhang keep reading?
This question is too childish.
Because it's daytime.
Right?
Wrong.
It's twelve o'clock at night.
After the power goes out,
you can't see your hand in front of your face.
But Old Zhang can still keep reading.
How is that possible?
That's impossible.
Absolutely impossible.
Tell me why.
The answer definitely won't hold water.
Old Zhang is blind.
He's reading Braille.
You can't even answer such a simple question.
How did you do your studying?
University, graduate school...
All for nothing.
You're worse than me, from the school of life,
a worker-peasant-soldier.
Honestly.
Coming up with two brain teasers isn't a skill.
If you're capable, let's...
compete in something else.
Compete in something else?
What other skills do you have?
Besides spouting a few phrases of a foreign language,
correcting a few typos,
and writing a few lousy critiques.
Tell me, what other talents do you have?
What else can you do?
I can do magic tricks.
I can make a living person disappear.
I can channel my energy and make you vanish.
Do you believe me?
I don't believe a word you say.
This old man is very wicked.
I'm a big living person.
You can make me disappear?
Did everyone hear that?
Professor Fan said,
he can make me disappear.
What are you shouting for?
Scared?
Afraid to face the masses?
Who's scared?
If you're not scared, channel your energy.
Do it.
Do it!
Fine, I'll do it.
But before I do, you have to cooperate with me.
Cooperate how?
Come on, um...
Stand with your legs straight.
Shoulder-width apart.
Come on, squat down.
Thighs and calves at a right angle.
Isn't that just a horse stance?
Here, hold this book.
Hold this book.
Pretend to read.
Why pretend?
I'm actually reading.
This is an English book of mine.
You can't understand it anyway.
Fine.
I'm going to start channeling now.
In the army, I could do this for an hour. Come on.
Hurry up
Done
Darn it
I'm still right here
Immovable
Don't be impatient
This power I'm channeling
Has a bit of a lag
You'll disappear completely in a minute
Let's time it now
Hello, Old Zhang
Alright
One minute on the clock
Start. Come on
Okay
It's just one minute
Channeling this power
I can hold it
I'm getting a bit tired
I'm going to replenish my qi
Go ahead. Okay
You keep this pose
Fine
If you move, it won't work
Got it
Okay, I'm going
Everyone watch, one minute
I haven't moved
Haven't moved
How is it?
Hello comrades. Hello
President Liang
Boss Li
What kind of kung fu are you practicing?
He...
Professor Fan said
He can make a living person disappear
Said if I stay still for a minute
When he comes back in a bit
I'll have disappeared
I don't think this looks like a disappearing act
What does it look like?
You look like a living person taking a dump
Alright, Old Fan
You dare trick me
Watch how I...
I'm going to fix you good
Old Fan
How did it go today? Who won?
Why you, Old Fan
What's going on?
Boss Li
Why did you scare the girl away?
Who scared...
I was just about to ask you
Right, I was just about to ask you
Why did you trick me?
Happy April Fools' Day
What are you cursing me?
Don't think I can't tell
Who cursed you?
I'm wishing you a happy holiday
Who are you fooling?
It's still a month until May Day
Who said May Day?
Today is April 1st, April Fools' Day
In English, it's called April Fools'
And in French?
Don't show off to me
I'm asking you why you tricked me
April Fools' Day
Is a holiday for pranks
You can't even take a joke
You're a sore loser
Who's a sore loser?
What April Fools' Day pranks?
Isn't it just everyone tricking each other?
You just wait
I'm going to trick you good today
April Fools' Day
Just you watch.
I'm gonna prank you so hard today you'll foam at the mouth.
Hello, President Li.
Xiao Chang.
What are you doing?
I felt a bit hungry.
Having a snack.
Then what's this?
The toothpaste.
Eating cookies while...
...brushing my teeth.
How can you eat cookies while brushing your teeth?
That's just it.
Aren't these dentures?
Alright.
President Li, let me introduce you.
Director Xu.
This is Director Xu from the TV station.
Hello, Director Xu.
President Li.
No need to be so formal.
Just call me Xiao Xu.
Young and promising.
Thank you.
Here's the thing.
Our station...
...has revamped the Life Channel.
We came to the retirement community today...
...to look for inspiration.
We have a program...
called "Aging with Purpose."
Good.
So...
You've heard all about my deeds.
I haven't done nearly enough.
In painting, I can't compare to Fan Zeng.
In calligraphy, I can't compare to Qi Gong.
In dancing, I can't compare to Yang Liping.
In piano, I can't compare to Kong Xiangdong.
I am ashamed.
Listen to that.
Mr. Li's standards for himself...
...are way too high.
Mr. Li.
Don't be so formal with me.
Just call me President Li.
How is the lighting in this room?
Do I need to...
...put on some makeup?
No...
President Li...
...you've misunderstood.
We came here this time...
...to look in this community...
...for a highly respected guest.
Yes.
Right?
We're not recording here.
We want to take him...
...to our station...
...to record there.
Is that so?
Then let's...
So the person we want to invite is your...
...roommate.
Right.
Professor Fan Dacheng.
Yes.
Is that so
It's actually okay
But about Professor Fan
Boss Li
The TV station's car
Is waiting outside
Why don't you tell us
Where Professor Fan went
Where did he go
How about this
I'll go get him for you
No, Boss Li
Don't trouble yourself with this
Let Xiao Fang or Zhu Zhu go
No
I have to be the one to get him
Why
Because today, my words
He won't
He won't disbelieve them
Why is that
He
He said he wants to break up with me
Maybe he
Was just speaking out of anger
Professor Fan has already blocked me
If that's the case, let me tell you
This works
What are you doing again
Why did you make the girl cry again
You
Lao Li, stop talking nonsense, will you
What do you mean nonsense
You tell me
What did you call me for
By the way
I have some very unfortunate news for you
What is it exactly
The TV station
Some program or other
Wants to do an episode on
Aging with Purpose
Dr. Chang recommended me
But I turned it down
Dr. Chang is so clueless
He recommended you instead
Lao Li
It doesn't matter what you say about me
But you can't slander Dr. Chang
Little Chang
He's the director of our retirement community
The way he looks at things
Is so sharp
Fine, sharp
I'm telling you
It's up to you whether you go or not
He's waiting for you inside
Then I'll just
You're tricking me again
I almost fell for your trap
What trap
I'm telling you
Believe it or not
They really are waiting for you inside
I won't go even if you talk the sky down
Not going
Don't you regret it
I won't regret it
I
The TV people really came
Look, would I fake that
They're waiting inside
Alright then, you go back first
I'll tidy up and go
Okay
Stop fishing
Hurry up
I'm not going back
Want to see me make a fool of myself
No way
Why isn't he back yet
Boss Li
Did you explain clearly to Professor Fan
I explained it clearly
Absolutely clearly
Your exact words, word for word
Professor Fan said
He'll catch one more big fish
And come back immediately
Should I go check again
No
No need
If Professor Fan Dacheng
really doesn't want to be interviewed,
then let's leave it for another time.
That would be
too embarrassing.
It's fine.
Let me tell you, Director Xu,
this Professor Fan,
he's definitely not unwilling to be interviewed.
And he didn't mean to be late.
He must have some unspoken difficulty,
or he's locking horns with someone.
Just wait a little longer.
All right.
Maybe we shouldn't wait.
Could you recommend someone else?
Recommend someone else... well,
on such short notice,
it's really hard to find someone.
What's so hard about that?
Far on the horizon,
yet right before your eyes.
President Li
You mean...
Professor Zhu from Longevity Residence next door?
Thanks for reminding me.
What did I remind you of?
Professor Zhu is reliable.
Professor Zhu.
Go do a pre-interview.
Let's go, follow me.
Okay.
Wait, what do you mean?
Did I just shoot myself in the...
Teacher Liu, April Fools!
Hello.
I wasn't talking about you.
Why are you so happy?
Well, I trade stocks.
And I made a small profit.
I'd like to treat you to a simple lunch today.
Oh, I couldn't possibly impose.
It's fine.
Where are we eating?
Let's use the private room in our canteen.
At 12:00 noon.
Be there or be square.
Just the two of us, right?
And Professor Fan.
Him too?
Of course he has to be there.
The reason I made money on stocks this time...
...is because of Professor Fan's expert advice.
Wouldn't it be inappropriate not to invite him?
That wouldn't be right.
Right, not right.
I called him, but he didn't pick up.
Is he around?
No.
When I see him later...
...I'll just tell him.
You tell him?
This matter...
...won't it make me look...
...completely insincere?
I have to go personally.
This thing...
...must be told by me.
Why?
Because...
...because right now...
...the person he trusts the most...
...is me.
Huh?
Why is that?
How could they just break up like that?
Doesn't the saying go...
"Better to destroy ten temples..."
"...than to ruin one marriage"?
They weren't married.
I know.
But you can't just split up like that.
Who is her boyfriend?
Not me.
He's not from our department.
His name is Wu Di.
He graduated from our school's Journalism College.
Him?
It doesn't matter which college he's from.
If his values are twisted...
...how can he produce good news?
Which unit does he work for?
I'll go have a word with his boss.
Auntie Cai.
Please don't.
What is it?
You still care about that Chen Shimei?
Listen, Xiao Cai.
Don't be impulsive, okay?
You can't just...
...ruin the kid's future over this.
Old Fan.
I finally found you.
I have some unfortunate news for you.
Why did you make the poor girl cry again?
Shoo.
What is it?
Spit it out.
Teacher Liu asked me to tell you...
...that today at noon...
...she's treating you to lunch.
How can that be unfortunate news?
That's wonderful news!
She's just inviting me, right?
Of course...
...and me.
That is indeed unfortunate news.
I'm telling you now.
12:00 sharp.
Second floor private room.
Be there or be square.
Be there or...
Not bad, Little Li
You've learned to use my weakness to trick me
That's progress
No
Who's tricking you?
If you don't believe me, let's go ask Teacher Liu
Fine, let's ask
Who are you trying to fool?
Once I ask her
and she says no such thing happened
you'll just stand there laughing at me
Right?
You...
Anyway, I've told you
It's up to you whether you go
Good thing I was extra careful
Or I would've been fooled by you, you old rascal
Auntie
Please listen to my explanation
Explain what?
What is there to explain?
I was the one who broke up with Xiao Xin
But it's not because I had a change of heart
or that I don't love her anymore
Ideals are full
but reality is harsh
That Xiao Xin
although she isn't a material girl
she's very clingy
After graduation
all she thinks about is
getting married and starting a family
supporting a husband and raising children
But look at my situation
I kept thinking when her birthday comes
I'd give her a new phone
But I've been working for six months
and haven't even saved a thousand yuan
I'm not afraid you'll laugh at me for saying this
look at this boxed lunch I'm eating
I couldn't even bear to add a soy egg
Child, you...
have it pretty hard too
How about this
Auntie Cai will add a chicken leg for you
Tell me
how could I bear to let her squeeze into a rental with me?
If she leaves me
she could find anyone she wants
I really don't want to drag her down anymore
Don't say anymore, don't say anymore
Your Auntie Cai
cries easily
You're going to make me cry
I'll go buy you a chicken leg first
You definitely told him
I did
Noon today, right here
I absolutely told him
I guarantee it on my character
Teacher Liu, don't you trust me?
Then why isn't he here yet?
That I don't know
Should I go invite him again?
No need for that
Let's eat first
Okay
Come on
President Li, listen to me
Teacher Liu is here too
Come
Play a couple of rounds with us
We'll follow
the rules set by the General Administration of Sport
No gambling
No, I don't know how
I don't know how to play, President Li
East, West, South, North, Red, Green, White
Watch four rounds and you'll get it
Just sit and watch a couple of rounds first
I'll teach you, I'll teach you
Come on
Give it a try
About our...
when will the physical exam results be out?
Should be soon
I heard Royal Physician Sun say
it seems they'll be ready this afternoon
President Li
I finally found you
Old Sun, what do you need me for?
You...
look at this X-ray
Here in the lungs
there's a noticeable shadow
Shadow
Isn't that cancer?
Someone pour me a glass of water.
Hurry.
Royal Physician Sun.
Tell me the truth.
How many days do I have left?
Boss Li.
This film isn't yours.
It's Professor Fan Dacheng's.
It's not me?
That's great!
No, it's not mine.
Then why did you show it to me?
I...
You'll scare someone to death.
I came to ask you...
...where Professor Fan Dacheng is right now.
Aren't you roommates?
With this condition, he must be re-examined immediately.
You guys keep playing.
I need to go find Professor Fan right away.
Teacher Liu, play a couple of rounds for me.
I don't know how.
I mean, we should probably go over there too.
Right.
Let's go check on him.
Let's stop playing for now.
This...
So the game's over?
Fan...
Professor Fan.
Stop reading.
Bad news.
You...
Are you going to tell me...
...some unfortunate news again?
At a time like this...
...you're still joking around with me?
This time, I really...
...bring you unfortunate news.
Royal Physician Sun just told me...
...that your lungs...
...have a shadow on them.
He said to go to the Medical Center for a re-check.
Oh my god!
Is it true?
This...
What are we going to do?
Stop with your little tricks.
Do you think I'm that easy to fool?
What tricks?
I'm telling you the absolute truth.
I must admit...
...the lie you made up this time...
...is quite creative.
It's quite sophisticated.
You really used your brain.
But when it comes to fooling me...
...you'd better come up with a better plan.
What creativity?
Royal Physician Sun told me personally.
He said there's a shadow on your lungs.
Look.
Is he here yet?
Professor Fan, we finally found you.
Hurry up, come with me to the Medical Center for a re-check.
Royal Physician Sun,
you, my elder,
such a highly respected gentleman,
are joining him to trick me too?
Naughty.
Professor Fan, we really aren't tricking you this time.
Old Liang, are you in on it with them too?
Shut up, stop babbling.
Go to the hospital.
I'm not going.
I won't fall for it.
Stop wasting breath on him.
Grab his arms and waist.
We're dragging him to the hospital today no matter what.
Okay.
Don't.
Don't move.
You, surnamed Li!
You can't play like this!
No, Old Fan...
Don't get excited.
President Li really...
and all of us just mean well.
Come on, hurry up.
What do you mean "mean well"?
I taught him about April Fools' Day, didn't I?
You guys...
Fine, everyone together.
Get him!
Stop it!
What April Fools' Day?
This April Fools' Day...
I'm telling you,
don't play with people's lives!
Easy now.
Easy! What are you doing?
Stop it!
It's for your own good.
You've all been tricked by Old Li!
Don't!
Seriously, stop messing around!
I kind of understand you young people now.
That Wu Di...
he doesn't have it easy either.
Auntie Cai,
you just went there once,
and you've already defected to "Di"?
It's not defecting.
That "Di"...
he has his difficulties.
Child,
you have to cherish your school days.
Once you step into society,
you have to fend for yourself entirely.
You can't count on your parents.
Wu Di was determined to break up with Xiao Xin.
There's no way to salvage it now.
I didn't complete the mission.
I don't even know
how to explain it to Xiao Xin.
Okay.
He added me back.
We aren't breaking up anymore.
For real?
What's the situation?
What happened?
Tell us.
Wu Di said
he received some profound education today,
and decided never to give up, no matter how hard it gets.
He'll stay with me through thick and thin.
You old rascal.
You actually came back?
Look at you.
You just ruled out the possibility of lung cancer,
and now you're blowing your top again.
That's really bad for your health.
Besides, what did I do to you today?
You really tricked me today.
I didn't trick you today.
Every word I said was the truth.
That is a trick!
You said you were going to trick me today,
but you actually didn't trick me.
That is the biggest trick of all!
You went back on your word!
I said I'd trick you,
but I didn't trick you,
yet you were tricked.
I kept my word.
How can you say I went back on my word?
Tricking you with lies...
that...
isn't real skill.
It doesn't show Boss Li's true mastery.
So?
Impressed?
Serves you right.
Choked on my biscuit, didn't you?
Luckily, I learned the Heimlich maneuver.
Move! Quick, move!
Boss Li, how are you?
Is it serious?
Should we call Royal Physician Sun?
Don't call Royal Physician Sun.
I only have myself to blame.
In that biscuit I gave you this morning,
I squeezed a tube of toothpaste.